Guide to the Abell family papers, 1797-1936.
Abell family papers, 1797-1936.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Abell family papers, 1797-1936.
1480
Abell family.
2 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, accounts, notebooks, receipts, insurance policies, photographs, school records, and miscellaneous papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, diaries, accounts, notebooks, receipts, insurance policies, photographs, and miscellaneous papers of the Abell family of Cazenovia.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, diaries, accounts, notebooks, receipts, insurance policies, photographs, and miscellaneous papers of the Abell family of Cazenovia. Papers of Dr. William Abell, a general practitioner (d.1835), include diaries, notebooks, correspondence, and loose notes on medical cases, travel; the status of the medical profession in Louisiana and secret societies in Cazenovia. Other papers include school records, instructions from the Commissioners of Roads of Cazenovia. Also included are genealogical and other correspondence and paper of or about Anna Abell, Aurella Abell, Caroline Jones, George Jones, Thomas Jones, George N. Manchester, Elisha Sanford, Henry Severance, and Ebenezer Whitney.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Abell family.; Abell, William, d.1835.
Subjects:
Medicine--New York--Cazenovia.; Medicine--Louisiana.; Voyages and travels.; Education--New York--Cazenovia.; Roads--New York--Cazenovia.; Secret societies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1798-1839 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1840-1936 and undated (Box 2)
- Genealogical notes (Box 2)
- MSS copy of Medical Laws of New York, ca. 1760 (Box 3)
- MSS notes on cure of erysipelas (bound in with An Act to Organize the Militia of the State of New York, 1818 ) (Box 3)
- Bye-Laws of the Chenango County Medical Society: 1822 (pamphlet) (Box 3)
- Student Clinical Notes at Norwich, 1820 (Box 3)
- Clinical Notes, 1821 (Box 3)
- Medical Case Book, 1830 (Box 3)
- Medical Case Book, 1830-1831 (Box 3)
- Medical Case Book, 1831-1832 (Box 3)
- Record of Fees Paid, 1831-1832 (Box 3)
- Webster's Calendar or the Albany Almanack, by Andrew Beers, Albany, N.Y. Copies - 1805-1815, 1817, and 1818 (Box 3)
- Family Almanack and Franklin Calendar, 1848, by George R. Perkins, Cazenovia, N.Y. (Box 3)
- An Address to the Different Religious Societies, on the Sacred Import of the Christian Name. 1814, Utica, N.Y. (Box 3)
- The Constitution of the Ancient Britons' Benefit Society, of the Village of Utica. By Augustine G. Dauby, Utica, 1824. (Box 3)
- Proceedings of the State Convention of Mechanics. Held at Utica, August 21st-22nd, 1834, For the purpose of taking into consideration the Effect produced on the Various Mechanical Trades by the Present System of State Prison Discipline. New York, N.Y., 1834 (Box 3)
- Broadsides and fragment of broadside (Box 3)
- Pass Book - Trust & Deposit Company of Onondaga in account with J.W. Abell, Sr., 1912-1920 (Box 3)
- News Clippings
  - Funeral of Mrs. Elizabeth Sims, n.d. but after 1827 (Box 3)
  - Article on the Able [sic] Family, from Illustrated Weekly Magazine, Apr. 22, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Article on Shaw Manor acquired by New London County Historical Society, from The Evening Post - Semi-Weekly, New York, Sept. 30, 1907 (Box 3)
  - 1928 Assessment Roll, Town of Cazenovia, from The Cazenovia Republican, Oct. 19, 1928 (Box 3)
- Farm Account Book 1797-1819 (Box 4)
- Farm Account Book 1826-1865 (Box 4)
- Farm Account Book 1830-1841 (Box 4)
- Farm Account Book 1833-1866 (Box 4)
- Diary and account book (Farm) 1833 (Box 4)
- Notebook of expenses, Horatio Abell, 1824-1835 (Box 4)
- Notebook of Asa S. Goodrich, 1847 (Box 4)
- Diary, 1864 (Box 4)
- Unfilmed material:
  - A Geometrical Decimal Interest Table ... Williams, Glidden and Coleman, Utica, 1815 (Box 4)
  - Announcement of lectures, Jefferson Medical College, Philadelphia, 1834 (Box 4)
  - A Catalog of Medical Books, Allen & Ticknor, Boston, 1832 (Box 4)
  - The Doctor at Home, Dr. B.J. Kendall, Enosburgh Falls, Vermont, 1884, Kendall Co. (Box 4)
  - The General Family Directory, New York, 1842, Comstock & Co. (Box 4)
  - Analytical First Reader, Richard Edwards & J. Russell Webb, 1866, New York, Taintor Brothers, Merrill & Co. (Box 4)
  - John Bull in America, Henry Severance, 1887, Dunkirk, New York, The Dunkirk Printing Co. (See manuscript poetry in collection.) (Box 4)
  - Musica Sacra; or Utica and Springfield Collections United, Thomas Hastings and Solomen Warriner, 1825, Utica, Willian Williams. (Box 4)
  - 19 Printed post cards giving Official Reports for Burlington, Cedar Rapids & Northern Railway, Aug.-Dec. 1877; Jan.-Dec. 1878; Jan.-Dec. 1879 (Box 4)
  - Scrap of paper redeemable for 10 cents, token of merit (Box 4)
  - 6 photographs (Box 4)
  - 4 tintypes (Box 4)
- Microfilm:
  - Boxes 1 and 2 (Reel 1)
  - Box 3 as far as "Record of Fees Paid, 1831-1832" (Reel 2)
  - Box 4 as far as "Diary for 1864" (Reel 3)
  - Box 3 from Webster's Calendar to end of box list (Reel 4)